stefanini.com 2019-07-18

# Stefanini Privacy Policy

**Information Security**

Stefanini is committed to being compliant to the EU General Data Protection Regulation. Find out the steps we are taking here.

The Top Management of Stefanini recognizes the importance of identifying and protecting the information assets of the organization, avoiding destruction, improper disclosure, improper modification or unauthorized use of any information relating to its customers, employees, pricing, strategy, management, or other related concepts.

Stefanini is therefore committed to develop, implement, maintain and continually improve the Information Security Management System (ISMS ) in order to ensure the confidentiality, availability and integrity of information.

To achieve this goal, Stefanini:

Establishes annual objectives in relation to Information Security.

Ensures the identification and fulfillment of business requirements, contractual, legal and regulatory obligations of security.

Develops a process of risk analysis, and, according to its results, implements the appropriate actions in order to address risks that are deemed unacceptable based on criteria established in the Risks Identification and Assessment process.

**Privacy Policy**

The Company respects individual privacy and values the confidence of its customers, employees, vendors, consumers, business partners, and others. The Company strives to collect, use and disclose Personal Information in a manner consistent with the laws of the countries in which it does business. The Company complies with the EU-US Privacy Shield and the Swiss-US Privacy Shield Frameworks as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries and Switzerland.This Privacy Policy (“Policy”) sets forth the privacy principles that the Company follows with respect to transfers of Personal Information anywhere in the world, including transfers from the European Economic Area (EEA) and Switzerland to the United States.

**Stefanini Privacy Statement**

Last Updated: June 2017

Stefanini participates in the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework. To learn more see: Stefanini, the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework

Your privacy is important to us. This privacy statement addresses information we collect at our web sites and in off-line sales and marketing activities. It explains what personal data we collect from you and how we use it.

The Stefanini Services Privacy Statement section provides additional information relevant to particular Stefanini products and services. This statement applies to the Stefanini products listed, as well as other Stefanini products that display this statement. References to Stefanini products in this statement include Stefanini services, apps, software and devices.

**Personal Data We Collect**

Stefanini collects data to operate effectively and provide you the best experiences with our products. Through your interaction with us, Stefanini may collect Personal Information, which is information that identifies an individual or relates to an identifiable individual. Personal Information may include, but is not limited to, your name, physical address, telephone number, e-mail address, company affiliation and associated interests.

Should you interact with our recruitment team, Stefanini may ask for certain data, including educational and employment background, contact information and preferences, job qualifications, and jobs for which you would like to submit an application. You also may choose to provide Stefanini additional information, such as your CV, resume, or transcripts; employment references and related information; and compensation requests. In addition, Stefanini may collect information from third parties, for example, in connection with a background or employment check and/or an employment reference.

Stefanini may also collect Other Information through your interaction with us and non-Stefanini websites, which does not reveal your specific identity or does not directly relate to an individual. Other Information may include, but is not limited to, browser and device information, data collected through automated electronic interactions, application usage data, demographic information, geographic or geo-location information, statistical and aggregated information.

Statistical or aggregated information does not directly identify a specific person, but it may be derived from Personal Information. For example, we may aggregate Personal Information to calculate the percentage of visitors in a particular region.

In some instances, we may combine Other Information with Personal Information, such as combining a precise geographical location with your name. If we combine Other Information with Personal Information, we will treat the combined information as Personal Information.

You have choices about the data we collect. When you are asked to provide personal data, you may decline. But if you choose not to provide data that is necessary to provide a product or feature, you may not be able to use that product or feature.

Stefanini will collect only Personal Information which is relevant for the purposes for which it is to be used. Stefanini will take reasonable steps to ensure that Personal Information is relevant, accurate, complete, and current, to its intended use.

**How We Use Personal Data**

Stefanini uses the data we collect for two basic purposes, described in more detail below: (1) to operate our business and provide (including improving and personalizing) the products and services we offer, and (2) to send communications, including promotional communications.

Business Operations. We use data to provide and improve the products and services we offer and perform essential business operations. We use data to develop aggregate analysis and business intelligence that enable us to operate, protect, make informed decisions, and report on the performance of our business and the services our customers’ desire.

Communications. We use data we collect to deliver and personalize our communications with you. For example, we may contact you by email or other means to invite you to participate in a survey. Additionally, you can sign up for email subscriptions and choose whether you wish to receive promotional communications from Stefanini by email or telephone. For information about managing email subscriptions and promotional communications, please visit the Access and Controls section of this privacy statement.

Recruitment. We use data we collect to communicate with you, to manage Stefanini’s recruiting and hiring processes, and for compliance with corporate governance and legal and regulatory requirements. If you are hired, the information may be used in connection with employment and corporate management.

**Reasons We Share Personal Data**

We share your personal data with your consent or as necessary to complete any transaction or provide any product you have requested or authorized. In addition, we share personal data among Stefanini-controlled affiliates and entities. We also share personal data with vendors or agents working on our behalf for the purposes described in this statement. For example, companies we’ve hired to provide customer service support or assist in protecting and securing our systems and services may need access to personal data in order to provide those functions. In such cases, these companies must abide by our data privacy and security requirements and are not allowed to use personal data they receive from us for any other purpose. We may also disclose personal data as part of a corporate transaction such as a merger or sale of assets.

Finally, we will access, transfer, disclose, and preserve personal data, including your content, when we have a good faith belief that doing so is necessary to:

comply with applicable law or respond to valid legal process, including from law enforcement or other government agencies;

protect our customers, for example to prevent spam or attempts to defraud users of our products, or to help prevent the loss of life or serious injury of anyone;

operate and maintain the security of our products, including to prevent or stop an attack on our computer systems or networks; or

protect the rights or property of Stefanini, including enforcing the terms governing the use of the services – however, if we receive information indicating that someone is using our services to traffic in stolen intellectual or physical property of Stefanini, we will not inspect a customer’s private content ourselves, but we may refer the matter to law enforcement.

Please note that some of our products include links to products of third parties whose privacy practices differ from Stefanini’s. If you provide personal data to any of those products, your data is governed by their privacy statements.

**How to Access & Control Your Personal Data**

Upon request, Stefanini will grant individuals reasonable access to Personal Information that it holds about them. In addition, Stefanini will take reasonable steps to permit individuals to correct, amend, or delete information that is demonstrated to be inaccurate or incomplete.

**Your Communications Preferences**

You can choose whether you wish to receive promotional communications from Stefanini by email and telephone. If you receive promotional email from us and would like to opt out, you can do so by following the directions in that message. If you do not wish to receive telephone calls from us, do not provide a telephone contact number.

**Browser-Based Controls**

Cookie Controls. Relevant browser-based cookie controls are described in the Cookies section of Stefanini’s website.

**Security of Personal Data**

Stefanini is committed to protecting the security of your personal data. We use a variety of security technologies and procedures to help protect your personal data from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. For example, we store the personal data you provide on computer systems that have limited access and are in controlled facilities. When we transmit highly confidential data (such as a password) over the Internet, we protect it through the use of encryption.

Stefanini’s security policies and procedures are reviewed and overseen by Stefanini’s Global Information Communication and Technology (ICT) Risk Management group. This group is responsible for security oversight, compliance and enforcement, and for conducting information security assessments and leading the development of information security policy and strategy.

Stefanini is also committed to reducing risks of human error, theft, fraud, and misuse of Stefanini facilities. Stefanini’s efforts include making personnel aware of security policies and training employees to implement security policies. Stefanini employees are required to maintain the confidentiality of data. Employees’ obligations include written confidentiality agreements, regular training on information protection, and compliance with company policies concerning protection of confidential information.

Stefanini promptly evaluates and responds to incidents that create suspicions of unauthorized handling of data. Stefanini’s Risk Management Group and Legal are informed of such incidents and, depending on the nature of the activity, define escalation paths and response teams to address the incidents. If Stefanini determines that your data has been misappropriated (including by a Stefanini employee) or otherwise wrongly acquired by a third party, Stefanini will promptly report such misappropriation or acquisition to you.

Stefanini will conduct annual compliance audits of its relevant privacy practices to verify adherence to this statement, EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework, and the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework Principles. The audit will be conducted under the direction of the Privacy Officer. Any employee that the Company determines is in violation of this privacy statement will be subject to disciplinary action up to and including termination of employment. Any Agent or Third Party that violates this privacy statement shall be in material breach of all agreements with Stefanini and shall defend and indemnify Stefanini from claims related to such violations.

**Where We Store and Process Personal Data**

Personal data collected by Stefanini may be stored and processed in your region, in the United States or in any other country where Stefanini or its affiliates, subsidiaries or service providers maintain facilities. We take steps to ensure that the data we collect under this privacy statement is processed according to the provisions of this statement and the requirements of applicable law wherever the data is located.

When we transfer personal data from the European Economic Area to other countries, we use a variety of legal mechanisms, including contracts, to help ensure your rights and protections travel with your data. Stefanini adheres to the principles of the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework, regarding the collection, use, and retention of data from the European Economic Area and Switzerland. To learn more about our adherence to these programs, please see: Stefanini, the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework

**Our Retention of Personal Data**

Stefanini retains personal data for as long as necessary to provide the products and fulfill the transactions you have requested, or for other essential purposes such as complying with our legal obligations, resolving disputes, and enforcing our agreements. Recruiting data is stored according to the maximum allowed retention periods according to the candidate’s location. Candidates can ask for deletion of their data at any time, if they don’t wish to keep up their application by notifying their recruiter or contacting the Privacy Officer of Stefanini.

When personal data is deleted, it is removed from live systems, but may remain in a backup format for up to one year. Data, whether in live or backup format, will be protected following the Security mechanisms described above.

**Changes to This Privacy Statement**

We will update this privacy statement when necessary to reflect customer feedback and changes in our products or services. When we post changes to this statement, we will revise the “last updated” date at the top of the statement. If there are material changes to the statement or in how Stefanini will use your personal data, we will notify you either by prominently posting a notice of such changes before they take effect or by directly sending you a notification. We encourage you to periodically review this privacy statement to learn how Stefanini is protecting your information.

**How to Contact Us**

If you have a privacy concern or a question for the Privacy Officer of Stefanini, please contact us by using the following contact information. We will respond to questions or concerns within 30 days.

Name Matthew D. Engler

Address 27100 W. 11 Mile Road, Southfield, MI 48034 USA

Phone +1 (248) 263-5678

Fax +1 (248) 386-4644

Email privacy@stefanini.com

Unless otherwise stated, Stefanini Corporation is a data controller for personal data we collect through the products or services subject to this statement.

Anja Hessler is our data protection representative for the country of Germany. The data protection representative can be reached at the following address: Stefanini Germany GmbH, Attn: Data Protection, Im Zollhafen 24, 50678 Cologne, Germany.

To find the Stefanini entity in your country or region, see http://global.stefanini.com.

**Stefanini Services Privacy Statement**

Last Updated: September 2016

Stefanini participates in the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework. To learn more see: Stefanini, the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework

The Stefanini Services Privacy Statement section provides additional information relevant to particular Stefanini products and services. This statement applies to Stefanini’s products and services and may include Stefanini services, websites, apps, software and devices. Stefanini established this privacy policy in order to clarify that the use of information to which it may be provided access in order to provide services is different than the use of information covered by Stefanini’s privacy statement.

Some services have their own, separate privacy agreements. In the event of a conflict between a Stefanini privacy statement and the terms of any agreement(s) between a customer and Stefanini, the terms of those agreement(s) will control.

To view our general privacy statement, please visit Stefanini Privacy Statement.

**Personal Information and Services Data We Collect**

Stefanini collects data to operate effectively and provide you the best experiences with our products. Through your interaction with us, Stefanini may collect Personal Information, which is information that identifies an individual or relates to an identifiable individual. Personal Information may include, but is not limited to, your name, physical address, telephone number, e-mail address, company affiliation and associated interests. This data is governed by Stefanini’s general privacy statement.

Stefanini may also collect Services Data. This is data that resides on Stefanini, customer or third-party systems to which Stefanini is provided access to perform services (including test, development and production environments that may be accessed to perform Stefanini consulting and support services). Stefanini treats services data according to the terms of this privacy statement, and treats services data as confidential in accordance with the terms associated with the service.

To illustrate the difference between personal information and services data, when a customer contracts with Stefanini for services, the customer provides information about themselves, including their name, address, billing information, and some employee contact information. Stefanini may also collect other information about the customer and some employees, for example through web sites, as part of that interaction. All of that information is personal information, and is treated according to Stefanini’s privacy statement.

In contrast, having contracted with Stefanini for services, the customer provides Stefanini access to its production, development or test environment, which may include personal information about its employees, customers, partners or suppliers (collectively “end users”). This information is personal information, and is treated according to Stefanini’s Services Privacy Statement.

Stefanini will collect only data which is relevant for the purposes for which it is to be used. Stefanini will take reasonable steps to ensure that this data is relevant, accurate, complete, and current, to its intended use.

**How We Collect and Use Services Data**

Stefanini uses the service data we collect for two basic purposes, described in more detail below: (1) to provide the products and services requested, and (2) to fulfill our contractual obligations.

To Provide Services and to Fix Issues. Services data may be accessed and used to perform services in compliance with your master services agreement or scope of work. The data we collect depends on the products and features you use, and can include the following:

Name and contact data. We collect your first and last name, email address, postal address, phone number, and other similar contact data during the course of providing services.

Credentials. We collect passwords, password hints, and similar security information used for authentication and account access.

Support Data. When you engage Stefanini for support, we collect data about you and your hardware, software, and other details related to the support incident. Such data includes contact or authentication data, the content of your chats and other communications with Stefanini support, data about the condition of the machine and the application when the fault occurred and during diagnostics, and system and registry data about software installations and hardware configurations.

Device data. We collect data about your device and the network you use to connect. It includes data about the operating systems and other software installed on your device, including product keys. It may also include IP address, device identifiers (such as the IMEI number for phones), regional and language settings.

Error reports and performance data. We collect data about the performance of the products and any problems you experience with them. This data helps us to diagnose problems in the products you use, and to improve our products and provide solutions. Depending on your product and settings, error reports can include data such as the type or severity of the problem, details of the software or hardware related to an error, contents of files you were using when an error occurred, and data about other software on your device.

Any copies of services data created for these purposes are only maintained for time periods relevant to those purposes.

To Fulfill Contractual Obligations. Stefanini may be required to retain or provide access to services data to comply with legally mandated reporting, disclosure or other legal process requirements.

Stefanini does not use services data except as stated above or in your master services agreement or scope of work. Stefanini may process services data, but does not control your collection or use practices for services data. If you provide any services data to Stefanini, you are responsible for providing any notices and/or obtaining any consents necessary for Stefanini to access, use, retain and transfer services data as specified in this statement and your master services agreement or scope of work.

**Reasons We Share Services Data**

We share your services data, with your consent or as necessary, to complete any transaction or provide any product you have requested or authorized. In addition, we share services data among Stefanini-controlled affiliates and entities. We also share services data with vendors or agents working on our behalf for the purposes described in this statement. For example, companies we’ve hired to provide customer service support or assist in protecting and securing our systems and services may need access to services data in order to provide those functions. In such cases, these companies must abide by our data privacy and security requirements and are not allowed to use services data they receive from us for any other purpose. We may also disclose services data as part of a corporate transaction such as a merger or sale of assets.

Finally, we will access, transfer, disclose, and preserve services data, including your content, when we have a good faith belief that doing so is necessary to:

comply with applicable law or respond to valid legal process, including from law enforcement or other government agencies;

protect our customers, for example to prevent spam or attempts to defraud users of our products, or to help prevent the loss of life or serious injury of anyone;

operate and maintain the security of our products, including to prevent or stop an attack on our computer systems or networks; or

protect the rights or property of Stefanini, including enforcing the terms governing the use of the services – however, if we receive information indicating that someone is using our services to traffic in stolen intellectual or physical property of Stefanini, we will not inspect a customer’s private content ourselves, but we may refer the matter to law enforcement.

**Security of Services Data**

Stefanini is committed to protecting the security of your services data. We use a variety of security technologies and procedures to help protect your services data from unauthorized access, use or disclosure.

Stefanini’s access to services data is based on job role/responsibility. Services data residing in Stefanini-hosted systems is controlled via the use of an account management framework. You control access to services data by your end users; end users should direct any requests related to their personal information to you.

Stefanini’s security policies cover the management of security for both its internal operations as well as the services. These policies, which are aligned with the ISO/IEC 27001:2013 standard, govern all areas of security applicable to services and apply to all Stefanini employees.

Stefanini’s security policies and procedures are reviewed and overseen by Stefanini’s Global Information Communication and Technology (ICT) Risk Management group. This group is responsible for security oversight, compliance and enforcement, and for conducting information security assessments and leading the development of information security policy and strategy.

Stefanini is also committed to reducing risks of human error, theft, fraud, and misuse of Stefanini facilities. Stefanini’s efforts include making personnel aware of security policies and training employees to implement security policies. Stefanini employees are required to maintain the confidentiality of data. Employees’ obligations include written confidentiality agreements, regular training on information protection, and compliance with company policies concerning protection of confidential information.

Stefanini promptly evaluates and responds to incidents that create suspicions of unauthorized handling of data. Stefanini’s Risk Management Group and Legal are informed of such incidents and, depending on the nature of the activity, define escalation paths and response teams to address the incidents. If Stefanini determines that your data has been misappropriated (including by a Stefanini employee) or otherwise wrongly acquired by a third party, Stefanini will promptly report such misappropriation or acquisition to you.

Stefanini will conduct annual compliance audits of its relevant privacy practices to verify adherence to this statement, EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework, and the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework Principles. The audit will be conducted under the direction of the Privacy Officer. Any employee that the Company determines is in violation of this privacy statement will be subject to disciplinary action up to and including termination of employment. Any Agent or Third Party that violates this privacy statement shall be in material breach of all agreements with Stefanini and shall defend and indemnify Stefanini from claims related to such violations.

**Where We Store and Process Personal Data**

Services data collected by Stefanini may be stored and processed in your region, in the United States or in any other country where Stefanini or its affiliates, subsidiaries or service providers maintain facilities. We take steps to ensure that the data we collect under this services privacy statement is processed according to the provisions of this statement and the requirements of applicable law wherever the data is located.

When we transfer personal data from the European Economic Area to other countries, we use a variety of legal mechanisms, including contracts, to help ensure your rights and protections travel with your data. Stefanini adheres to the principles of the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework, regarding the collection, use, and retention of data from the European Economic Area and Switzerland. To learn more about our adherence to these programs, please see: Stefanini, the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework

**Our Retention of Personal Data**

Stefanini retains services data for as long as necessary to provide the products and fulfill the transactions you have requested, or for other essential purposes such as complying with our legal obligations, resolving disputes, and enforcing our agreements. When services data is deleted, it is removed from live systems, but may remain in a backup format for up to one year. Data, whether in live or backup format, will be protected following the Security mechanisms described above.

**Changes to This Privacy Statement**

We will update this privacy statement when necessary to reflect customer feedback and changes in our products or services. When we post changes to this statement, we will revise the “last updated” date at the top of the statement. If there are material changes to the statement or in how Stefanini will use your services data, we will notify you either by prominently posting a notice of such changes before they take effect or by directly sending you a notification. We encourage you to periodically review this privacy statement to learn how Stefanini is protecting your information.

**How to Contact Us**

If you have a privacy concern or a question for the Privacy Officer of Stefanini, please contact us by using the following contact information. We will respond to questions or concerns within 30 days.

Name Matthew D. Engler

Address 27100 W. 11 Mile Road, Southfield, MI 48034 USA

Phone +1 (248) 263-5678

Fax +1 (248) 386-4644

Email privacy@stefanini.com

Anja Hessler is our data protection representative for the country of Germany. The data protection representative can be reached at the following address: Stefanini Germany GmbH, Attn: Data Protection, Im Zollhafen 24, 50678 Cologne, Germany.

To find the Stefanini entity in your country or region, see http://global.stefanini.com.

**Stefanini, the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework**

Stefanini, Inc. and its controlled U.S. entities (Stefanini) complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union and Switzerland to the United States. Stefanini has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles. If there is any conflict between the terms in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification, please visit https://www.privacyshield.gov/.

Stefanini’s participation in the Privacy Shield applies to all personal data that is subject to the Stefanini Privacy Statement and is received from the European Union, European Economic Area and Switzerland. Stefanini will comply with the Privacy Shield Principles in respect of such personal data.

Stefanini’s accountability for personal data that it receives under the Privacy Shield and subsequently transfers to a third party is described in the Privacy Shield Principles. In particular, Stefanini remains responsible and liable under the Privacy Shield Principles if third-party agents that it engages to process the personal data on its behalf do so in a manner inconsistent with the Principles, unless Stefanini proves that it is not responsible for the event giving rise to the damage.

As further explained in the “How to Contact Us” section of the Stefanini Privacy Statement, we encourage you to contact us should you have a Privacy Shield-related (or general privacy-related) complaint. Questions or complaints regarding this Policy and any privacy-related issue should be submitted by mail or email to the Privacy Officer, as indicated below:

Name Matthew D. Engler

Address 27100 W. 11 Mile Road, Southfield, MI 48034 USA

Phone +1 (248) 263-5678

Fax +1 (248) 386-4644

Email privacy@stefanini.com

Any questions or concerns regarding the use or disclosure of Personal Information should be directed to the Privacy Officer. Stefanini will investigate and attempt to resolve complaints and disputes regarding use and disclosure of Personal Information in accordance with the principles contained in the privacy statement. For complaints that cannot be resolved between Stefanini and the complainant, the company has agreed to participate in the dispute resolution procedures of the International Centre for Dispute Resolution / American Arbitration Association (“ICDR/AAA”) in accordance with its applicable commercial rules as well as the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Principles; provided further that any arbitrator shall be either an attorney or retired judge having significant and recognized experience with, and knowledge of, privacy issues and information technology. Please refer to the ICDR/AAA’s website for more information: http://go.adr.org/privacyshield.html. All decisions of the arbitration panel shall be final and binding on the parties, which waive any right to further appeal the arbitration award, to the extent an appeal may be lawfully waived. Further, Stefanini will use the European Data Protection Authorities (DPA) as its independent recourse mechanism with respect to European Union human resources data. Stefanini will use the Swiss Federal Data Protection and Information Commissioner as its independent recourse mechanism with respect to Switzerland human resources data.

Stefanini is also subject to the jurisdiction of the US Federal Trade Commission. The Federal Trade Commission may be contacted at the following address:

Federal Trade Commission

Attn: Consumer Response Center

600 Pennsylvania Avenue NW

Washington, DC 20580

USA

consumerline@ftc.gov

www.ftc.gov

**Cookies**

**What are cookies?**

A cookie is a small text file that is stored on your computer when visiting a website. This text file stores information that can be read by the website when visiting it again at a later date. Cookies can be installed by the server of the website you visit or by partners of that website.A website’s server can only read the cookies it has installed itself, and has no access to other information found in your computer or mobile device. Cookies are stored in the folder of your browser on your computer or mobile device.

Cookies generally make the interaction between the visitor and the website faster and easier, and help the visitor navigate between the different parts of a website. Some of these cookies are necessary because otherwise the site is unable to function properly. Other cookies are convenient for the visitor: they remember your username in a secure way as well as your language preferences, for example. Cookies mean that you do not need to fill out the same information each time you visit a website.

**How does Stefanini use cookies?**

Stefanini uses cookies to help us provide you with a better user experience tailored to your personal preferences. By using cookies Stefanini makes sure that you do not receive or need to enter the same information every single time you visit the Stefanini website. Cookies are also used to optimize the performance of the website. Different kinds of cookies are used on Stefaninis’ websites:

Necessary cookies

Functional cookies

Performance cookies

Advertisement cookies

**Necessary cookies**

These cookies are indispensable for visiting our websites and using certain parts of the websites. For instance, they allow you to navigate between the different parts of the website, and fill in forms. If you refuse these cookies, certain parts of the website will not work, or will not work optimally.

**Functional cookies**

Functional cookies are cookies that make it easier for our websites to work, make them more pleasant for visitors, and ensure that you have a more personalized browsing experience. For example, these cookies can remember your language choice and customer segment.

**Performance cookies**

We use performance cookies to obtain information about visitors’ use of our websites, in order to improve the content of our websites, adapt them to the wishes of visitors, and make them more user-friendly. For instance, there is a cookie that counts the number of unique visitors, and a cookie that keeps track of the most popular pages.

**Advertisement cookies**

Cookies for remarketing – This website uses cookies which, based on the pages you visit on this website, keeps a tally of the products or services you may be interested in. Through these cookies and with the tools of the Google advertising network (Google Analytics), we can show you ads on other websites that are part of Google’s advertising network for products and services you may be interested in. This technique is called “remarketing”. These cookies do not contain any personal data.

Act-On – Stefanini utilizes Act-On software. Act-On is a software-as-a-service product for marketing automation developed by Act-On Software. When you visit our website, Act-On collects demographic details and profile data and stores them anonymously in an advertisement cookie. Advertisement cookies do not contain personal data. The information collected via these cookies are used to tailor the products and services you may be interested in when on our website.

**How to disable cookies?**

Firefox

1\. Open Firefox.

2\. At the top of the Firefox window, click the “Firefox” button and then select “Options.”

3\. Select the panel “Privacy”

4\. Set “Firefox will:” to “Use custom settings for history”. Uncheck the “Accept cookies from sites” option to disable cookies.

5\. Click “OK” to close the options

Internet Explorer

1\. Open Internet Explorer.

2\. Click the “Tools” button and click “Internet Options.”

3\. Click the “Privacy” tab and then “Settings”, move the control up to block all cookies, and then click “OK”

Google Chrome

1\. Open Google Chrome.

2\. Click the icon of the tool.

3\. Select “Settings.”

4\. Near the bottom of the page, click “Show advanced settings.”

5\. In the “Privacy”, click “Content settings” section.

6\. To disable cookies, select “Block site settings of any data”.

Safari

1\. Open Safari.

2\. Choose “Preferences” in the toolbar and click on “Privacy” (You can find the toolbar that looks like a gear, top right in Safari window.)

3\. In the “Block cookies” section, you can specify if and when Safari should accept cookies from sites. To see an explanation of the options, click the help button (question mark)

4\. If you want to see which sites store cookies on your computer, click Details.
